In 1923, a black town in Florida was burned to the ground, its people murdered because of a lie. Some escaped and
survived because of the courage and compassion of a few extraordinary people. This film is for them.
Rosewood is a drama, history, action film directed by John Singleton.
Spurred by a white woman's lie, vigilantes destroy a black
Florida town and slay inhabitants in 1923.
Mann, played by Ving Rhames.
John Wright, played by Jon Voight.
Sylvester Carrier, played by Don Cheadle.
Duke Purdy, played by Bruce McGill.
James Taylor, played by Loren Dean.
Beulah (Scrappie), played by Elise Neal.
Rosewood is a 1997 American historical drama film directed by John Singleton, inspired by the 1923
Rosewood massacre in Florida, when a white mob killed black people and destroyed their town.
It stars Ving Rhames as an outsider who comes into Rosewood and inspires
residents to self-defense, wielding his pistols in a fight.
The supporting cast includes Don Cheadle as Sylvester Carrier, a resident who was a witness, defender of his family and
victim of the riot; and Jon Voight as John Wright, a sympathetic White store owner who lives in Rosewood.
The three characters become entangled in an attempt to save people from
racist White people attacking the Black residents of Rosewood.
Despite generally favorable reviews, the film was not a commercial success and
was unable to recoup its $17 million budget at the box office.
The film was entered into the 47th Berlin International Film Festival.
The film explores themes of small town, sheriff, racial
segregation, based on true story, race riot.
The tone is emotional and intense.